First we have a temperature sensor
which turns on the AC
as soon as the temperature rises.
Next we have a flame sensor
that alerts us in case of fire.
We also have a rear sensor
that detects when we're nearing an object
and triggers a buzzer.
Next, we have a rain sensor
that automatically activates
the windshield wipers,
and finally
a light sensor that switches
on the cars headlights
when it detects darkness.
All of this data is collected
and sampled in real time.
Moving on to our web platform,
customers log in to a home page
that greets them and presents
a map of the current location,
complete with live traffic data
and nearby fuel stations.
Customers can also submit
any questions they may have.
And a site administrator
will respond promptly.
They can also add vehicles
to their fleet and view real time data
along with insightful
statistics while filtering
that information
for any time period they choose.
Administrators can view
every vehicle in the system,
delete cars and filter
records
by customer name.
They also receive
and handle customer enquiries.
Another feature available
to both customers and administrators
is vehicle data comparison.
Customers can compare only their own cars,
whereas the admin can select
any car in the
system for comparison.
We've also developed a mobile app
that mirrors all the features
of the web interface.
It adds extra convenience
for our customers
and delivers push notifications
whenever
the in vehicle sensors detect fire,
a collision or interior movement
that could signal
a theft attempt.
The alerts rely on the flame sensor,
accelerometer and motion sensor
installed in each
car.